# IVAN STARODUBTSEV

**Embedded Software Engineer** 

### INFO

#### **ADDRESS**

Milky Way/Orion-Cygnus Arm/Solar System/Earth/Ukraine/Kyiv

#### **PHONE**

+380679262642 / Telegram

#### **EMAIL**

ivan.starodubtsev.name@gmail.com

# LINKS

github.com/lorrrn

# **SKILLS**

Programming languages: C (strong), C++ (confident), Python (confident).

Programming techniques: crossplatform development, multithreading programming, IPC, networking programming, REST API, unit testing, functional testing, device drivers development, OS-based (Linux, VxWorks, FreeRTOS) & no-OS/bare metal.

Development tools: GCC, binutils, terminal (sh/bash/fish), build systems (make, cmake, gn), debuggers (GDB, valgrind, strace, static code analysis), virtualization (QEMU), VCS (git, svn, perforce, clearcase).

# **PROFILE**

Software engineer with vast majority of experience in developing embedded software for different products from home surveillance to industrial instrumentation & control systems, from level of board support package & device drivers to user-land applications.

Extroverted & open minded, responsible & focused on challenging activities, mentoring experienced, had customer negotiations & project requirements development.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Sr. software engineer, Ring

Kyiv, Ukraine

Jan 2019 — Jan 2020

Home surveillance products: embedded software development, maintenance, troubleshooting & bug fixing, new features development including increasing product stability.

#### Sr. software engineer, SoftServe

Kharkiv, Ukraine

Jul 2017 — Dec 2018

Network security appliance with in-browser VPN: legacy code maintenance, troubleshooting & bug fixing.

#### Sr. software engineer, eZLO

Kharkiv, Ukraine

Jun 2016 — Jun 2017

Home security sensors hub: new features development, troubleshooting & bug fixing, sensors integration.

#### Sr. software engineer, CUJO

Kharkiv, Ukraine

Aug 2015 — May 2016

Home network adaptive firewall appliance: developing new product embedded software from scratch, porting numerous opensource projects into one box, troubleshooting, optimization, bug fixing.

# Software engineer, Echostar

Kharkiv, Ukraine

Jul 2013 — Jul 2015

Multimedia delivery platform: new features development, support, troubleshooting & bug fixing.

# Software engineer, GlobalLogic

Lviv, Ukraine

Dec 2012 — May 2013

Board support package for real-time applications: developing device drivers, troubleshooting & bug fixing.

#### Software engineer, Echostar

Kharkiv, Ukraine

Nov 2011 — Nov 2012

Multimedia delivery platform functional testing application: developing new features, troubleshooting & bug fixing.

#### Software engineer, Impulse

Severodonetsk, Ukraine

Kharkiv, Ukraine

Apr 2010 — Oct 2011

Industrial instrumentation & control system: developing embedded software, conducting its integration into huge industrial process automation system.

# **EDUCATION**

# Masters degree, National Aerospace University "Kharkiv Aviation Institute"

Sep 2004 — Mar 2010

Radio-technical faculty, Electronic devices specialization